i think you might have answered this in
a way already but i'll try and make it
brief
um so
given that it's um the crisis that's
happening and it might be coming in
waves
um have you already come across any
evidence of institutions or governments
implementing new ideas that point in a
game b direction um i guess in short is
it all just shenanigans or
are there any optimistic signs yet
oh this is nice so check check this out
i'll show you how i think it works
um it's a bit tricky but when you get
you get sensitive to it you'll see it
let's see
all right so imagine
if you've ever played that game with a
uh
parachute when you're a kid you all kind
of get around and you hold it you pull
it taut and you're carrying things
all right so imagine that and imagine
that's that's the the institutional
structures we're familiar with right now
and
there's stuff heavy stuff on the on the
on the tarp people are trying to carry
it
the the but but then imagine that
there's a oh
wait maybe this is even better no i
can't do that one yet
um but there's a different place
like a totally different thing over here
over to the right
and nobody's picking it up and nobody's
carrying it
and you've got a bunch of folks who are
holding that and they're carrying it
they're lifting it they're moving along
that's game a right that's the world we
live in and that and that's the stuff on
that tarp is the things that is our
lives or the things that we're carrying
and um every time somebody
who's holding on to that tarp looks over
and sees this over the thing over here
and they kind of nudge the person next
to him and kind of like hey that thing
over there
that's the game b piece and the that's
it's the
the awakening and the awareness of the
reality of the embeddedness of people
inside the environment who actually have
the right capacity and competence
now this is happening a whole lot right
it doesn't
it's not obvious right shenanigans are
the nature of the beast
the beast cannot but do shenanigans but
the beast at the end of the day
isn't a thing right it's an emergent
property of a whole lot of people
collaborating
and being willing to give their energy
and intentionality to the maintenance of
the beast
to the degree to which those individuals
are beginning to be aware of the
possibility and the necessity of no
longer giving their energies to the
beast and the reality of being able to
give their energy somewhere else
that proliferation it's like a
like a hollowing out an ossification and
you've ever seen uh
uh the way a bone looks with the holes
the micro micro elements this micro
dissolution of the integrity of the
coherent coordinating structure that
gives rise to the emergent beast
and as the most talented individuals
right the people who actually see game b
first from the inside of these kinds of
structures almost invariably are
unique in some way i don't mean
necessarily unique in a good way but
they're unique in some way
um
they're sensitive they can feel the
possibility and they feel the pain of
the beast and their complicity in the
beast in a uniquely powerful way and
they try to figure out
how do they continue to participate in
what's happening to make it as good as
possible but as they continue to watch
what's happening there are starting to
find each other
i can't name a lot of names here but
it's happening very rapidly
truly competent good people skillful
smart are beginning to just say you know
what fuck it
this thing is not working i need to just
get on the phone and call the guy i went
to college with who had to shit together
and see what he's up to and see if i can
collaborate with him
and then i'm going to figure out how to
create permission to do it inside the
thing that i'm doing
which is the way that it always works
best anyhow if you've ever been
inside some shitty corporate environment
you always know the only things that
ever happened when people actually
create
capacity peer-to-peer inside the
environment well in this case it's doing
is happening
super rapidly and across the entire
system
and we actually have a whole lot of
people who are incredibly capable
and have learned a lot of skills about
things like counter insurgency
and um uh intelligence
you know it's it's a it's a different
ballgame in the 1950s
so that i think is a way to think about
it and what we have to do is we have to
become increasingly conscious and
mindful
of how to because remember we don't want
to drop the ball in this thing
unfortunately
that thing that that tarp that i was
talking about the thing it's holding
that's our lives and if we let go of it
our lives fall with it and that gets
really bad really fast
so we have to actually find a way to
kind of like get the music to slow down
and then have the capable hands the
truly capable hands
increasingly steer what's happening
inside like it's a fabric that lifts up
and weaves itself underneath and so
people are actually held in something
that's real
and then we begin to move over to this
new attractor as people kind of point at
it
so yes i am seeing some things happening
inside what we would call existing
institutions it largely
correlates with the degree to which
those constructs are made up of people
who are
close to reality let me can i can i feed
one more piece of theory in here
i was talking about with somebody just
today and i think it's actually very
useful
i was asking the question of why it is
the dairy diet went wrong
because i got to tell you dairy dog went
wrong and the reason why i went wrong
i'm pretty sure
is because when the pipes burst in his
apartment
he did not fix those pipes himself in
fact in all likelihood he didn't even
call the plumber
he had to talk to the supervisor
supervisor called the plumber the
plumber fixed the pipes which is to say
that dairy dog was a first person
experience of bode vr simulation
the farther you are away from reality
the more likely it is that you will find
yourself playing in simulation space
which means you're going to lose the
thread you're going to have to play
games by
capital in social signaling manipulating
or getting other people to do the stuff
you want to do
instead of having to actually be
directly bound to reality
so the people in institutions who happen
to be directly bound to reality
they're the ones who are actually
starting to have to figure things out
the people who are the furthest away
from reality the ones that are the
deepest in the simulation
they're the ones who are actually very
confused and or dangerous
and so we have to figure out a way to
decouple their capacity to make choices
and or rapidly upgrade their sense
making if they happen to be amenable to
it
so that's a long-winded way of trying to
answer your question apologies if it
wasn't very tight
thank you
[Music]
you